- Hey, guys. - Hey.
-嗨  大家  -嗨
Honey, I got us that room
亲爱的  这周末我有订到
at the Woodford lnn this weekend.
那个伍德福特饭店
That place in Vermont? You can take a hint.
就是在佛蒙特的  我的暗示果然有用
You can't go away this weekend.
你们这周未不能外出啊
It's Emma's birthday.
那天是艾玛生日
We're having a party.
会有一个派对
Can't you have the party when we get back?
能不能等我们回来再举办呢
No. It won't be her real birthday.
不要啊  那就不是她真正的生日
Gee, if only she were 1
如果她就一岁
and had no idea what the hell a birthday was.
也不知道生日到底是什么就好了
Come on, you guys, this is really important to us.
这对我们很重要呢
Sorry, but Chandler and l could really
很抱歉  我和钱德勒真的
use a weekend away...
希望一起度个假日
...you know, to reconnect, emotionally.
我们想沟通沟通  心理上的
There's this thing I really want us to do.
我们从以前就很想做这件事
Maxim:美国男性杂志
我在《马克西姆》杂志看到的
Well, can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
你们可以选择其他日子吧
Yeah, we want everyone to be there.
我们非常希望大家都能来...
As much as I hate to delay your doing
当然我也抱歉耽误你
weird sex stuff to my little sister.
对我妹妹做那些奇怪性事
And, I mean, you know, you guys, this is a big deal.
你们听着  这是一件大事呢
How can we have her first birthday party
没有姑姑和姑父陪伴
without her aunt and her uncle?
让她怎么度过她的一岁生日
All right, we'll stay.
好的  我们会留下来
We can just drive up after the party.
完事儿再开车过去
Fine. But if we end up
好吧  如果派对的事情
not doing this Maxim thing because of this party--
害我们没做杂志上的事情
Believe me, that is not why we won't be doing that.
那不是不做的理由  好不好
《老友记》第十季第四集 艾玛的生日蛋糕
《老友记》  第十季  第4集 艾玛的生日蛋糕
You know, Pheebs,
你知道吗  菲比
when I was little, on my birthday...
我小的时候过生日...
...my daddy would hide a present
我爸会在家里
in every room of the house.
每个房间藏礼物
And then he would draw a treasure map
然后会给我们"宝藏地图"
to help me find them all.
叫我们自己找
I love family traditions like that.
我喜欢这种家庭习俗
When Ursula and I were kids,
我跟厄休拉小的时候
on our birthday...
过生日
...our stepdad would sell his blood
我们的继父会去卖他的血
to buy us food.
来买吃的
- Hey, guys. - Hi.
-嗨  大家  -嗨
I brought the camera for Emma's video.
我带了摄像机  来录艾玛的派对
Oh, good!
喔  好呢
We had this idea to make a birthday video for Emma...
我们想要录艾玛的派对
...and we'll give it to her when she's 18.
当她十八岁时  再拿给他看
Oh, cool.
酷
- Wow, it's like a time capsule. - Yeah.
-就像一个"时空胶囊"  -是啊
Oh, just think, she's gonna be watching that video on a TV...
想象一下  到时她就会用一个现在还未发明的
...that hasn't even been invented yet...
电视机来看这个影带
...with friends who, right now, are just, like, babies.
跟现在和她一样还是婴儿的朋友一起看
And they'll be living in a floating city that the humans built...
然后  他们住在一个浮起来的城市
...to escape the ant people.
为了逃避蚂蚁人
That's the hope.
希望是如此
So is Emma awake yet?
所以  艾玛起来了吗
No, it's still naptime.
没有  现在午睡时间
But she'll be up soon.
不过  马上她就醒了
Where's Joey?
乔伊在哪里呢
I said, it's still naptime.
我说过了  现在是午睡时间
- Hey, there's Uncle Joey. - Hey.
-嗨  乔伊叔叔来了  -嘿
Hey, say something to Emma on her 18th birthday.
说句话给十八岁生日的艾玛吧
- Eighteen, huh? - Joey, no!
-十八岁了  -乔伊  不要
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
怎么啦  怎么啦  是要给她很辣的朋友
When they see this, you'll be 52.
当她们看到这个  你已经是五十二岁了
And starting to think about settling down.
就是我开始想稳定下来的时候呢
Joey, will you please set this up for people
乔伊  帮我把这个支起来
to put Emma's presents on?
这样就可以放艾玛的礼物
Love to. Yeah.
非常愿意呢
We were supposed to bring presents?
我们要给她礼物吗
Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
是啊  我写了一首歌给艾玛
Oh, yeah. How was I supposed to know?
我怎么会知道呢
Joey, it's a birthday party.
这是一个生日派对啊
Yeah, but for a 1-year-old.
是啊  但她仅一岁而已
What's the point?
有什么意义
The other day she laughed for an hour at a cup.
那天她对着杯子大笑一个多小时
Elmo:《芝麻街》卡通形象
只是一个普通杯子上面有阿母穿的像农夫的图案
And he's standing next to this cow, and the cow says, "El-moo."
阿母站在牛旁边  牛说  "阿母..."
Man, that's a funny cup.
真是好笑的杯子
- Hey. - Hey.
-嗨  -嗨
Where's the birthday girl?
生日的女主角呢
Oh, she's still napping.
她还在睡觉呢
She was probably up all night excited about the party
当然  她昨晚知道要办一个派对
she knows is happening.
肯定太兴奋了  睡不着
I know you guys really want to get to Vermont,
我知道你们很想去佛蒙特
and this isn't a big deal to you.
对你们也是一件大事
But it really is to us, okay?
但这对我们也是一件大事  好吗
Emma will never have a first birthday again.
艾玛不会再有第二次的一岁生日
You're right. We're sorry.
好的  你对  我们很抱歉
Let's wake up Emma
那把艾玛叫醒
and get the fun time started!
开始派对吧
She didn't sleep well last night, so we can't wake her.
她昨晚睡不好所以我们不能叫醒她
Are you frigging kidding me, Greene?
你是不是在跟我开玩笑啊  姓格林的
- Hi! - Hey!
-嗨  -嗨
I'm so glad you came.
很高兴你们来了
I can't believe Emma's already 1.
真不敢相信  艾玛已经一岁了
I remember your first birthday.
我还记得你的一岁生日
Ross was jealous of all the attention we were giving you.
罗斯很嫉妒我们把注意力都放在你身上
He pulled on his testicles so hard...
他很用力地去拉他的蛋蛋
...we had to take him to the emergency room.
我们不得不要带他去看急诊
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
有些关于你爸爸的事情你还不知道
Hey, Mr. And Mrs. Geller.
盖勒先生和太太
Let me help you with that.
我帮你放下来吧
- Thank you. - Oh, man, this is great, huh?
-谢谢  -太好了
The three of us together again.
我们三个又聚在一起
You know what would be fun?
你们怎样会更有趣吗
If we gave this present
就当做这礼物是我们三个人
to Emma from all of us.
一起送给艾玛的
Which one are you?
你是哪一位啊
I can't believe Emma's still asleep.
真不敢相信  艾玛还在睡
I know. What are we gonna do?
我知道  怎么办啊
I've got a plan. I've got a plan.
我有计划  一个好计划
I'm going to ram this platter
我会把这个盘子
really hard into your ribs.
很用力的砸到你肋骨上
You're gonna scream out,
那你会痛的哇哇大叫
and that'll wake her up.
这样会吵醒她
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
我不会和这种莫妮卡去佛蒙特的
Hey, Pheebs? You know what?
嗨  菲比  你知道吗
I was thinking since you wrote a song...
即然你写了歌给艾玛
...maybe I could do something for Emma using my talents.
那我也可以用我的才能给艾玛做些事
So you're gonna hit on her?
所以  你要去泡她
No, no, no. My talents as an actor.
不是  不是啦  我的才能是表演啊
You know, I could, like, maybe....
我可以  可以...
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
给她边读本书边演出来
Or you could stick a fork in an apple.
或是  你可以把一个叉子叉在苹果上
Hey, I think Emma might like it.
我想艾玛会喜欢的
Oh, Emma might like what?
艾玛会喜欢什么
- My present. - What did you get her?
-我的礼物  -你要给他什么
We prepared performances.
实际上  我们正准备一个表演
Separate performances.
分开的的表演呢
But equally real.
但都是真的
That sounds like fun.
听起来好好玩了
People are getting a little antsy
你知道吗  因为大家很不耐烦
waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
要等艾玛起来
So would you mind performing them once now?
所以  你们可以现在表演一个吗
- Sure, yeah! - Okay.
-当然可以  -好...好  那好吧
Okay. All right. Everybody, let's get this party started.
大家听着  我们开始吧
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform a little something for us.
乔伊和菲比要表演给大家看呢
Oh, great.
太好了
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed
那你会不会觉丢脸
having nothing prepared?
上去没东西演
I do it every week
我每个礼拜经历这样的事情
with three cameras pointed at me
三台摄像机对着我
and a whole crew waiting.
整个剧组在等
So, Joey, what are you gonna do for us?
那乔伊你要表演什么呢
I will be doing a dramatic reading of one of Emma's books.
我会生动地演读一本艾玛的书
Oh, okay. Which one?
好耶  哪一本
Well, it's one of her favorites.
哇  他的收藏的其中一个
"Riding the Storm Out: Coping With Postpartum Depression."
《从暴风雨中脱险:对抗产后的抑郁症》
Love You Forever.
《爱你永远》
"Love You Forever, by Robert Munsch.
《爱你永远》作者:罗柏·曼
Published by Firefly Books. Printed...
萤火虫出版社出版
...in Mexico.
在墨西哥印刷...
A mother held her new baby
一个母亲抱起她的婴儿
and very slowly rocked him...
慢慢的  往前摇  往后摇
...back and forth,
往前摇  往后摇...
And while she held him, she sang,
当母亲抱着时  她唱了
I'll love you forever.
我会永远爱你
I'll like you for always.
我会一直喜欢你
As long as I'm living...
只要我还活着
...my baby you'll be.
我的孩子
"And while he rocked her, he sang:
当他抱着她时  他唱了
I'll love you forever.
我会永远爱你
I'll like you for always.
我会一直喜欢你
As long as I'm living...
只要我还活着
...my baby you'll be.
我的孩子
Oh, wow!
哇
That was amazing.
真的太棒了
Thank you so much for that gift.
真的非常感谢你的礼物
I was not ready for this today.
我今天没有这个心理准备
- Amazing. Amazing. - Phoebe, I'm sorry.
-太棒了  太棒了  -菲比  抱歉
Phoebe has prepared something as well.
菲比也要表演给大家看
That's right.
没错
I prepared a song for Emma,
我准备了一首歌给艾玛
from my heart to hers.
这首歌让我俩的心相连
For there's no greater gift than the gift of music.
没有比音乐更好的礼物了
Emma Your name poses a dilemma
艾玛  你的名字给我一个困境
'Cause not much else rhymes with "Emma"
和你名字押韵的字极少
Maybe the actor Richard Crenna
也许仅有演员理查德·克里纳
He played the commanding officer in Rambo
他曾出演《蓝波》中的长官
Happy birthday, Emma
生日快乐  艾玛
Is that it?
就这样
No, of course not.
不  当然不是  还有
No, I've also, you know, prepared a reading.
其他...  我也要读一本书给他
"Sex and the Single Mother."
《性爱和单身母亲》
- "Finding your G-spot." - Oh, no, no, no!
-找到你的G点  -不要啊
Hello, Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
嗨  艾玛  祝你十八岁生日快乐
Right now, that seems so far away, 17 years.
如果从现在算起  还有十七年之久呢
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then,
到时候你已经长大了
and we'll be....
而到时候我们...
Well, your grandfather and l might not be here.
你爷爷和我可能都不在了
That's true. This message could be coming to you...
没错  这信息可能是从阴间
...from beyond the grave, Emma.
传给你的  艾玛
After all, my parents died very young.
毕竟我父母亲很年轻就过世了
And my cholesterol's off the charts.
我的胆固醇还过高呢
Remember, Emma,
艾玛  请记住
heart disease kills women too.
女生也会死于心脏病
Okay, cut! Great. Great. That was just....
好了  停  这样就够了
Oh, good.
哦  好的
Ross, don't forget to get a shot of Emma's cake.
罗斯  别忘了要拍蛋糕
- It's in a box in the fridge. - Okay, sure.
-盒子在冰箱里  -好的  没问题
You're gonna love this cake.
你会喜欢这蛋糕
I got it from a bakery in New Jersey,
我从新泽西州的面包店买来的
Carino's.
加理诺面包店
Oh, my God, that place has the creamiest frosting!
他们有全世界最好吃的奶油
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
我小时候喜欢搭便车去那里
Well, anyway,
无论如何
they make these great novelty cakes...
他们可以做很多新颖的蛋糕
...in all different shapes.
也很多种造型
And if you give them a photo,
如果你自己准备照片
they'll copy it in icing.
他们还会放到蛋糕上
Did you do a picture of Emma?
那你一定放艾玛的照片喽
Yes. On a cake shaped like a bunny.
当然  在一个兔子形的蛋糕
Rach?
瑞秋
Does this bakery by any chance also bake...
这家店是不是刚好
...erotic cakes?
也卖色情蛋糕
Say, for bachelorette parties?
或许给单身派对使用
Ross, what are you talking--? Oh, my God!
你在讲什么啊  喔  我的天啊
They put my baby's face on a penis!
他们还把我女儿的脸放在"小弟弟"上
Now it's a party!
这才像派对嘛
Wait, you guys, this isn't funny.
这一点都不好笑
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster,
如果我想让这蛋糕成为一场灾难
I would have baked it myself!
我可以自己做啊
Is it okay
我还是觉得它很好吃啊
that I still think it looks delicious?
这样没问题吧
Jack, look at this.
杰克  你看看
I know what you're thinking, Judy.
我知道你在想什么
The resemblance is uncanny.
其相似程度非常惊人
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
我也差点再度拉我的蛋蛋
No, no, this is not what I ordered, okay?
不  不是  这不是我要订的
I went all the way to New Jersey
我特地去新泽西
so that I could have the perfect cake...
只为了我女儿有完美的生日蛋糕
...for my daughter's birthday. And I need a bunny cake right now!
还有  我需要兔子蛋糕  现在
Ask them if it would be faster
如果要快点的话
if we cut the baby's face off the penis...
我们可以从"小弟弟"上取出孩子的照片
...so we could put it on the bunny.
再贴到兔子蛋糕上
That is a weird sentence.
这句话太奇怪了
Oh, believe you me, I am going to bring this cake back.
相信我  我会把蛋糕换回去
I don't even want it in my home.
甚至我不想有这种蛋糕放在我家
Joey. Don't touch it!
乔伊  不要碰
I'm so confused!
我很疑惑啊
Yes, I still want my daughter's picture,
是的  我还是要我女儿照片
but on a bunny cake!
但是在兔子形状的蛋糕上
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting with nuts!
黄色蛋糕  有巧克力霜和坚果（nuts:坚果  也指男性睾丸）
nuts:坚果  也指男性睾丸
公平来讲  你说的东西这上面的确有
Mon, it was nice of you to loan Rachel your car...
莫妮卡  你真好啊  把车借给瑞秋
...so she could get the cake.
让她可以去换蛋糕
It was nice of her to pull my hair...
谢谢她一直揪我头发
...till I dropped the key.
直到我把钥匙丢了
Well, while we're waiting,
既然闲着
you could tape your message to Emma...
你们就先录一段
...for her 18th birthday, huh? Okay?
给艾玛的十八岁生日的祝福  好不好
Hi, Emma. It's the year 2020.
艾玛  现在是2020年
Are you still enjoying your nap?
你还在享受你的午觉吗
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle Chandler, by the way.
我们是莫妮卡姑姑和钱德勒姑父
You may not recognize us...
你可能不认识我们
...because we haven't spoken
因为我们已经十七年
to your parents in 17 years.
没有和你父母亲讲话了
We used to be married.
我们曾经结过婚
But then we missed a weekend away together,
但我们搞砸了我们的一个周末
and things kind of unraveled...
造成我们分开
...because of you.
就是因为你
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
Ross, Rachel promised
罗斯  瑞秋答应过
it would be over by now.
派对这时候会完
We seriously have to go
我们如果要去佛蒙特
if we want to get to Vermont.
现在该出发了
I called them,
我打电话问过他们了
the last train leaves in a half-hour.
最后一班火车在半小时后
And I have a massage client soon.
我有要按摩的客户
You guys, just, please, a little bit longer.
大家忍耐一下
I promise,
我保证
Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
瑞秋随时会带蛋糕回来
Monica, remember the frosting, huh?
莫妮卡  记得该店的奶油味道吗
All right, five more minutes.
好吧  我再等五分钟
Hello?
喂
Oh, no, what happened?
不是吧  发生什么事
Okay, okay, where are you?
好的  好的  你在哪里
Okay, I'll be right there.
我马上过去
Was that Emma?
是不是艾玛
Is she up?
她起来了吗
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
瑞秋因超速被警察拦下来
She forgot her license.
他忘了带驾照
I have to bring it to her.
我得送过去
If you're leaving, I'm definitely going.
如果你要走那我也得走
Wait, if anybody gets to go, it's us!
如果有人要走那就是我们
We've been complaining the longest!
我们是抱怨最久的
No, wait, you guys. No, you can't leave.
等等  你们不能走
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
蛋糕的事已让瑞秋很烦
How do you think she'll feel
如果回来时发现大家不在
when she comes back and you're gone?
那她会怎么想
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
我不知道  你礼拜一才会告诉我们
Joey, you're in charge, okay?
乔伊  你负责这里
You make sure nobody leaves.
谁也不许走
Got it!
了解
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
嘿嘿嘿  你要去哪
To the bathroom.
去洗手间啊
Well, the rest of you get comfortable,
大家怎么舒服怎么来
because we are gonna be here for a--
因为我们还要待在这...
Wait, there's a window in there.
等等  洗手间里有个窗户...
No! He's not getting away that easy!
不要让他逃走
What are you doing?
你们干什么啊
Get the hell out of here!
快滚出去啊
Well, that one did not have Emma's face on it.
那个"小弟弟"上没有艾玛的照片
- No, it did not. - No.
-是  没有  -对
Well, we'd better get going. It's late.
已经很晚了  我们真的要走了
Jack can't drive at night anymore.
杰克不能在晚上开车了
He has trouble staying in his lane.
他不能保持在自己的车道里
Last winter I went up on a church lawn
去年冬天我开车经过教堂的草地
and drove right through a manger scene.
然后撞上马的食槽
The papers thought it was a hate crime.
报纸误以为那是报复性犯罪
- Anyway, it was lovely seeing you. - Okay.
-无论如何  很高兴可以见到你们  -好的
- Bye. Bye, dear. - Nighty-night.
-再见  -晚安
- Nighty-night. - Bye.
-晚安  -再见.
How could you just let them leave?
乔伊  你怎么可以让他们走
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿嘿嘿
I'm not gonna mess with Jack.
我不会和杰克过不去的
He's a great man. He fought for our country.
他是一个能为国家而战的伟人
No, he didn't.
他才没有呢
He pretended to be a Quaker
他装成贵格会教徒
to get out of Korea.
才可以逃离韩国
Well, that's it. He's the last one to go.
够了  他是最后一个退出的
I'm locking you guys in.
我把门锁上了
You do know I can just turn them
你知道那个锁是
the other way around, right?
可以从这里面打开的
Oh, I forgot you used to live here.
我忘了你以前住过这里
- Hello? - Joey, it's Estelle.
-喂  -乔伊  我是埃斯特尔
- Hey. - So how'd your audition go today?
-嗨  -你今天的试镜如何
What audition?
什么试镜
The one I told you about last week.
上礼拜我和你是过的啊
What? You never said anything about an audition.
什么  你根本没有说过任何试镜
Let me start over.
那我重新说
I just got a call about an audition.
我刚接到一个试镜通知
I think you can still make it.
你现在去还来得及
It's down at the Astor Theater,
就在紫苑戏院
and you need to have a monologue prepared.
还要自己带独白
A monologue? I don't have a--
独白  我没有...
I got it.
有了...
So I'm gonna take off.
那我要走了
What?
什么
No, wait! You don't get to leave.
不  等等  你不能走
I've got a massage client waiting outside my door any minute.
我有按摩客户会随时到我家门外呢
And we paid for a room
房间的钱我们已经付了
that we're supposed to be in right now!
我们早该在里面
Well, okay, now...
好好
...only one of us has to stay with Emma.
只要有一个人照顾艾玛就行了
Okay, and as the person who realized that, I get to go.
因我刚发现这点所以我可以走了
No...
不行...
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
那我们想一个较公平的方法来决定谁要留下来
Oh, I got it.
有了
Okay, everyone pick a number from one to 10, all right?
大家选择一到十的数字
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
谁选到最大的数字可以先走
Okay, 10.
好喔  我选"十"
Okay, Monica picks 10. I call nine.
莫妮卡选"十"  那我选"九"
Anyone else?
还有其他的吗
- No, let's just draw straws. - Okay.
-大家来抽签吧  -好
Or we could flip a coin and multiply the answer--
或是可以扔硬币  答对次数...
- I'm begging you to stop. - Right.
-拜托你  不要讲话了  -好  .
Okay, how about this?
这样好啦  我们从艾玛的
We got wind-up toys for Emma.
生日礼物选一个发条玩具
We can make them race,
拿来赛跑
and whoever comes in last stays.
哪个跑最后的  就要留下来
Yeah, let's do that!
好吧  就这样
That sounds more fun than the thing
这好像比我们要
we were gonna do in Vermont!
在佛蒙特做的事情好玩
Okay, everybody, pick your toys!
好  各位  开始选玩具吧
Okay. I want the dolphin!
我要用那个海豚
- That's a bear! - I'm too excited!
-那是一只熊  -我太兴奋了
Phoebe, you get the bear.
菲比  你用这只熊
Joey, you get the robot.
乔伊  你用机器人
Oh, yeah.
哦  好的
And Chandler and I get the dog.
钱德勒就用这只狗吧
And the race is going to go from here to here.
比赛就  从这里到这里
Now, the one who comes in last stays!
谁最后一名的  留下来
Okay, ladies and gentlemen,
各位先生及女士
wind your toys.
卷好你的发条
Okay. On your mark, get set, go!
准备了吗  预备  开始
Go! Go!
快  快
Come on, robot!
不要停  机器人
What are you barking at?
你叫什么呢
Well, how is that gonna help?
那个动作有什么用
I bought you!
我买的你
How did I forget that that's all you do?
我竟忘了你只会这个动作
Way to go, robot!
好样的  机器人
Good job, Alan.
干得好  熊熊
Hey, good race, you guys.
真的一个好比赛
Yeah, see you later.
是啊  那就再见喽
No. No, no. Wait.
不  不  你们等一下
We didn't lose.
我们没有输呢
The rules clearly stated that
规则是说
the last one to cross the finish line was the loser.
最后跑到终点才是输家
Well, our dog never crossed
那我们的狗
the finish line. So technically--
没有跑到终点  所以...
They left.
他们已经走了
There isn't time to go to the bakery.
根本没时间去面包店
We're gonna come home.
所以我们现在回家了
Everybody left?
大家已经走了
All right. Well, just tell Emma
好吧  告诉艾玛
that we'll be there as soon as we can. Bye.
我们会尽快回家  再见
- Rachel! - Oh, God, sorry!
-瑞秋  -喔  天啊  抱歉
I can't believe they gave you a ticket.
真不敢相信  他们给了你一个罚单
You're such a good driver.
你是多好的驾驶员
- Emma's awake. - Yeah?
-艾玛醒了  -是喔
I can't believe this.
真不敢相信
This is her first birthday,
在她的一岁生日
she's awake, we're not even there.
她醒来时我们不在
Everybody left.
大家也都走了
We still have this stupid obscene cake.
还加上这个烂蛋糕
Hey, maybe I can fix that.
也许我可以弄好这蛋糕
You know, try to turn it into something else.
试试看  改成别的形状嘛
Oh, don't even bother.
已经无所谓了
We've already ruined her first birthday.
我们已经毁了她的第一个生日
And do you know
你不知道
how important these early experiences are,
这些早期的经验对她有多重要吗
Ross? Very!
罗斯  非常重要
According to the back cover of that book that you gave me.
你给我的那本书背面是这么说的
Rach, she's not gonna remember this.
瑞秋  她不会记得这些
I guess.
也许吧
Oh, I just had such an idea
我本来想像着
of what this day would be like, you know?
今天会是怎样的一天
Emma laughing...
艾玛在笑
...and everybody gathered around her cake,
大家围绕着蛋糕
singing "Happy Birthday."
唱"生日快乐"
And then we would all--
然后我们...
Hey, get out of the road,
嘿  不要挡老娘的路
you stupid student driver!
白痴新手
They have to learn.
他们总要学这点
- Hey. - What?
-嘿  -什么
This is not bad.
这样不错嘛
Oh, my God. Look, you made it into a bunny.
天啊  你把它变成小兔子了
How did you do that?
你怎么弄的
Well, I just made these two things cheeks.
我把这俩东西改成脸颊
And then I split this to make ears.
把这东西分成两份  变成耳朵
Well, I am very impressed.
我非常感动呢
Some can sing, some can dance.
有些人会唱歌  有些人会跳舞
I, apparently, can turn phallic cakes
我显然的可以
into woodland creatures.
把"小弟弟"改成兔子蛋糕
Now, another way to organize your stuffed animals
还有另外一种方法来整理玩具
is by size.
就是按照大小
I'm sorry, is this a game
对不起  这是给艾玛玩的游戏
for Emma or for Monica?
还是给莫妮卡
Game?
游戏
Emma, do you even know it's your birthday today?
艾玛 你知道今天是你生日吗
You're 1.
你一岁了
One year old. That's little.
就是一岁  这么小
That's my girl.
好丫头
That's how old you are.
这就是你的年龄
Did I teach her that?
是我教她的吗
Did I just impart wisdom?
我传授智慧给她
I want one.
我也想要有一个
Me too.
我也是
There's no one around.
这里又没人
Why don't we just take this one?
干脆我们把这个带走
- And head to Canada. - I was kidding.
-然后跑去加拿大  -我在开玩笑
I wasn't. Let's get going.
我可没有呢  快点出发吧
Hey, are Ross and Rachel back?
嘿  罗斯和瑞秋回来了吗
No, not yet.
还没有呢
Oh, good, I didn't miss the party.
喔  好耶  我没错过派对嘛
What about your massage client?
那你的按摩客户呢
I just felt so bad missing this.
我觉得很内疚如果错过这派对
So I just slipped him a little something, you know.
所以我给他吃了点东西
As long as I'm back in five or six hours,
只要我五或六个小时后
it'll be all right.
能回去就行
Okay.
好
If Ross and Rachel ask,
如果罗斯和瑞秋问起我
I've been here the whole time. The whole time.
就说我一直待在这里  一直
I've been here the whole time.
我一直待在这里的
Joey, we just saw you come in.
乔伊  我们刚看到你进来
You ran past us on the stairs.
而且你跑上来时  在楼梯有超过我们
I don't care that you left.
我不管你有没有离开
I'm just glad that you're here.
我很高兴你们现在在这里
Thanks, you guys.
谢谢大家
Hey, guys, come on.
大家过来
You gotta see what Emma just did.
你们应该看看艾玛刚做了什么
- What? - Emma, how old are you?
-什么  -艾玛  你几岁
How old are you today?
你今天几岁
Emma, that's right. You're that many.
对了  艾玛就是那么一岁
Oh, my God, our daughter's a genius.
天啊  我们女儿是一个天才
- This means-- - No! No science camp!
-这表示...  -不要有科学的说教了
Damn it! I'll put a candle on the cake.
真是的  我把蜡烛放到蛋糕上
Oh, and, Emma, look at your stuffed animals
艾玛  看看你的娃娃
lined up so neatly.
排得如此整齐
Thanks.
谢谢
Okay, here we go.
好了  来了
Emma's first birthday cake.
这是艾玛第一个生日蛋糕
Go ahead, Emma, blow out the candle.
快吹啊  吹灭蜡烛
Come on, Emma. You can do it.
快  艾玛  你能做到的
What's wrong? Are you okay?
怎么啦  你还好吧
Oh, yeah, nothing.
喔  没事
These are happy tears.
这是快乐的眼泪
This is just what I wanted.
这就是我想要的
Hey, you made it into a bunny.
蛋糕已变成兔子形状的
What is wrong with me?
我怎么啦
It looked more delicious when it was a penis.
为什么我觉得"小弟弟"的形状时看来比较好吃
- Okay, you ready? - Yeah.
-好  准备了吗  -是的
- And record. - Okay.
-那  开始录了  -好
Hi, Emma.
嗨  艾玛
Well, your first birthday is over, and--
你的生日刚结束了  而且...
Go! Go! Come on!
快啊  快啊
Go! Go, Alan! Run, you hairy bastard!
熊熊  快跑啊  你这只笨熊